Mathematical Writing (CS 209) Videorecordings V0174
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Mathematical writing (CS 209) videorecordings
1987
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Knuth, Donald Ervin
V0174
3.75 Linear Feet 30 videotapes (VHS)
Videotaped lectures from Knuth's computer science course Mathematical Writing, given in the fall of 1987; guest lecturers were Herb Wilf, Jeff Ullman, Leslie Lamport, Nils Nilsson, Mary-Claire van Leunen, Rosalie Stemer, and Paul Halmos.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Administrative transfer, 1998.
Information about Access
Open for research. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Professor of computer science at Stanford University.
Description of the Collection
Videotaped lectures from Knuth's computer science course Mathematical Writing, given in the fall of 1987. The course focused on issues of technical writing and the effective presentation of mathematics and computer science. Guest lectures included Herb Wilf (University of Pennsylvania), Jeff Ullman (Stanford), Leslie Lamport (Digital Equipment Corporation), Nils Nilsson (Stanford), Mary-Claire van Leunen (Digital Equipment Corporation), Rosalie Stemer (San Francisco Chronicle), and Paul Halmos (University of Santa Clara).
The class notes are available as a Stanford report, Mathematical Writing, and a published book.
Mathematics--Authorship.; Halmos, Paul R. (Paul Richard); Knuth, Donald Ervin; Lamport, Leslie.; Nilsson, Nils J.; Knuth, Donald Ervin; Stanford University. Computer Science Department; Stemer, Rosalie.; Ullman, Jeffrey D.; Van Leunen, Mary-Claire.; Wilf, Herbert S.
- Videos
  - Mathematical writing, 174.01 (Box 1)
  - Minicourse on technical writing (1), 1983 Oct 2; 174.2; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 1)
  - Minicourse on technical writing (2), 1987 Oct 5; 174.3; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 1)
  - Comments on student answers (1), 1987 Oct 7; 174.4; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 1)
  - Comments on student answers (2), 1987 Oct 9; 174.5; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 1)
  - Preparing books for publication (1), 1987 Oct 12; 174.6; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 1)
  - Preparing books for publication (2), 1987 Oct 14; 174.7; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 1)
  - Preparing books for publication (3), 1987 Oct 16; 174.8; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 1)
  - Herbert Wilf, guest lecturer, Presenting Algorithms, 1987 Oct 19; 174.9; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 1)
  - Literate Programming (1), 1987 Oct 21; 174.10; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 1)
  - Literate Programming (2), 1987 Oct 23; 174.11; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 1)
  - User manuals; Galley proofs, 1987 Oct 26; 174.12; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 2)
  - Herb Wilf, guest lecturer, on Mathematical Writing, 1987 Oct 28; 174.13; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 2)
  - Refereeing (1), 1987 Oct 30; 174.14; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 2)
  - Refereeing (2), 1987 Nov 2; 174.15; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 2)
  - Illustrations (1), 1987 Nov 4; 174.16; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 2)
  - Illustrations (2), 1987 Nov 6; 174.17; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 2)
  - Quotations, 1987 Nov 9; 174.18; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 2)
  - Scientific American Saga (1), 1987 Nov 11; 174.19; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 2)
  - Scientific American Saga (2), 1987 Nov 13; 174.20; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 2)
  - Examples of good style, 1987 Nov 16; 174.21; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 2)
  - Jeff Ullman, guest lecturer, on Getting Rich, 1987 Nov 18; 174.22; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 2)
  - Leslie Lamport, guest professor, on Writing Papers, 1987 Nov 20; 174.23; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)
  - Nils Nilsson, guest lecturer, on Art and Writing, 1987 Nov 23; 174.24; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)
  - Mary-Claire van Leunen, guest lecturer, 1987 Nov 25; 174.25; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)
  - Comments on student work, 1987 Nov 30; 174.26; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)
  - Mary-Claire van Leunen, guest lecturer, 1987 Dec 2; 174.27; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)
  - Computer aids to writing, 1987 Dec 4; 174.28; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)
  - Rosalie Stemer, guest lecturer, on Copy Editing, 1987 Dec 7; 174.29; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)
  - Paul Halmos, guest lecturer, on Mathematical Writing, 1987 Dec 9; 174.30; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)
  - Final truths, 1987 Dec 11; 174.31; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)